<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Homebrewing with the Oaf</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Homebrewing with the Oaf</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 16:13:20 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theoafidian.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mead Batch #1: Of the bees and the beers</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 16:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-1/</guid><description>Honey Mead: Bees and Beers Ingredients We&amp;rsquo;re aiming for a first, simple batch of 5 litres, using local bee honey.
7L of Brewing water: the water from the faucet is quite hard, therefore the ion contents are dilluted by mixing it with distilled water in a 2/1 ratio. around 1.25 kg&amp;rsquo;s local honey Applejack&amp;rsquo;s Mead Yeast Spoonful of citric acid or juice from two lemons Half a cup of strong tea Brewing Mix honey and water and bring to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Beer Batch #2: Czech Pilsner: Decoctions</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-2/</guid><description>Czech Pilsner: Concoctions Ingredients Brewing water: the water from the faucet is too hard for this type of beer. Therefore the ion contents are dilluted by mixing it with distilled water in a 1/1 ratio. 2 kg&amp;rsquo;s of Bohemian pilsner malt Saaz Hop pellets. Brewing Decoction Decoction is a process where part of the mash is separated from the larger part and boiled. This process was traditionally repeated 3-4 or more times and helped to get the most out of the malt.</description></item><item><title>Cider Batch #1: Backyard Apples &amp; Hop Bells</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 20:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-1/</guid><description>Backyard Apples &amp;amp; Hop Bells Cider Ingredients Backyard picked hop from a friend, dried and stored before use. 2,5 baskets of apples from our yard, stored in the fridge. Pressing Total of 5L pressed Specific gravity: 1.050 -&amp;gt; estimated 6.5% EtOH after fermentation 500 mg Campden added for 24h in cooking pot with rag to allow evaporation Primary Fermentation Originally the plan was to do primary fermentation in a fermenting bucket and have a second fermentation in a Damme-Jeane.</description></item><item><title>Tools</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/tools/</guid><description> Alcohol By Volume Calculator Priming Sugar Calculator Brewing Water Chemistry</description></item></channel></rss>