<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Batches on Homebrewing with the Oaf</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/</link><description>Recent content in Batches on Homebrewing with the Oaf</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mead Batch #3: Melafika</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-3/</guid><description>Fika If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever met a Swede, you&amp;rsquo;ve heard about fika. Fika is all about having yourself a dark roast, some sweets and good company and take the time to have a chat. The only thing that could still be missing in this utopian concoction would be&amp;hellip; Mead?
Therefore Mel and fika, a pun on the word malefica which is an old timey way of saying witch.
Ingredients As a first experiment a small batch of 5L is made, the honey during primary is a cheap store honey.</description></item><item><title>Beer Batch #5: This shit's bananas</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-5/</guid><description>Banana beer People have been using bananas to ferment alcoholic beverages for the ages throughout Africa. Traditionally sorghum flour is mixed with ripened bananas (Matoke/Musa acuminata) and fermented to an orange, sweet, lightly hazy drink. Different countries have their own spin on the beer and their own names for the brew; mubisi (Uganda), urwaga (Kenya) and kasiksi (DR Congo) to name a few. In Tanzania their banana beer called mbege is even brewed commercially.</description></item><item><title>Beer Batch #4: een pintje d'Abbey</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-4/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-4/</guid><description>Experimenting with oak A simple abbey beer, augmented with vanilla infused oak chips. A batch of 5L was made with:
Pintje d&amp;#39;Abbey 1kg Bohemian pilsner malt or any other pils malt, but I still had this around 300g Abbey malt 40g of Saaz hop (definetly try other hops, but again I still had this lying around) a teaspoon of Irish Moss a packet of M47 abbey yeast about 8g of Oak chips Hopping schedule The following hopping schedule is used:</description></item><item><title>Mead Batch #2: Pulque Fiction</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-2/</guid><description>Agave Mead: &amp;ldquo;Pulque Fiction&amp;rdquo; Pulque is a traditional alcoholic beverage was made from fermenting the aguamiel (loosely translated to mead)from agaves in ancient Mexico. It is a highly sugary substance that completes fermentation in under two days. It has an opaque, milky color and a viscous texture. The drink turns more slimy as it reaches the end of its shelf life, which is not long as it spoils quite soon. Pulque fermentations contain a large nuber of wild bacteria and yeast, which are the cause of the remarkable speed at which it ferments and spoils.</description></item><item><title>Cider Batch #2: Backyard Apples</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 20:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-2/</guid><description>Backyard Apple Cider Ingredients 2,5 baskets of apples from our yard, used fresh from the tree. Pressing Total of 5L pressed Specific gravity: 1.050 -&amp;gt; estimated 6.5% EtOH after fermentation Add 500 mg of pectinase to break down pectines 500 mg Campden added for 24h in cooking pot with rag to allow evaporation One Stop Fermentation After treatment with campden:
sanitization recipient, airlock and tools used half a tablespoon of yeast nutrients added SafCider yeast pitched and waterlock placed After 2-3 days, an intense Rhino fart smell 👃💩😰 filled the air while CO2 production could be seen.</description></item><item><title>Wine Batch #1: Boiling Backyard Grapes</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/wine-batch-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2023 20:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/wine-batch-1/</guid><description>Backyard Grapes Sour Wine Ingredients About 3 baskets of backyard picked grapes from a friend, boiled and filtered. Preparation of the juice Whole grapes were boiled for about 40 mins juice from a lemon and 2 bags of rooibos tea were added Juice was filtered trough strainer and cooled to RT sanitization recipient, airlock and tools used 5L Juice transfered to glass damme Jeanne. Pectinase was added for 8hs One Stop Fermentation half a tablespoon of yeast nutrients added SafCider yeast pitched and waterlock placed There was some overflow in the airlock the first few days due to intense fermentation of the sugar-&amp;gt;CO2 by the yeast.</description></item><item><title>Mead Batch #1: Of the bees and the beers</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/mead-batch-1/</guid><description>Honey Mead: Bees and Beers Ingredients We&amp;rsquo;re aiming for a first, simple batch of 5 litres, using local bee honey.
5L of Brewing water: the water from the faucet is quite hard, therefore the ion contents are dilluted by mixing it with distilled water in a 2/1 ratio. around 1 kg of local honey Applejack&amp;rsquo;s Mead Yeast Juice from a lemon Half a cup of strong tea (Earl Grey) Brewing Mix honey and water and bring to a boil.</description></item><item><title>Beer Batch #3: Czech is back</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-3/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-3/</guid><description>Return of the Czech The previous recipe was followed for a batch of 10L, but the hopping schedule was adapted.
New Hopping schedule The following hopping schedule is used:
The water was brought to a boil before hopping.
17g of hop was added at the start 7 g of hop was added after 30 min another 7 g was added after 45 min with a total cooking time of an hour.</description></item><item><title>Beer Batch #2: Czech Pilsner: Decoctions</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2022 23:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/batch-2/</guid><description>Czech Pilsner: Concoctions Ingredients Brewing water: the water from the faucet is too hard for this type of beer. Therefore the ion contents are dilluted by mixing it with distilled water in a 1/1 ratio. 2 kg&amp;rsquo;s of Bohemian pilsner malt Saaz Hop pellets. Brewing Decoction Decoction is a process where part of the mash is separated from the larger part and boiled. This process was traditionally repeated 3-4 or more times and helped to get the most out of the malt.</description></item><item><title>Cider Batch #1: Backyard Apples &amp; Hop Bells</title><link>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 20:13:20 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://theoafidian.github.io/batches/cider-batch-1/</guid><description>Backyard Apples &amp;amp; Hop Bells Cider Ingredients Backyard picked hop from a friend, dried and stored before use. 2,5 baskets of apples from our yard, stored in the fridge. Pressing Total of 5L pressed Specific gravity: 1.050 -&amp;gt; estimated 6.5% EtOH after fermentation 500 mg Campden added for 24h in cooking pot with rag to allow evaporation Primary Fermentation Originally the plan was to do primary fermentation in a fermenting bucket and have a second fermentation in a Damme-Jeane.</description></item></channel></rss>